Ojasvi Dev Tamang

Backend PHP Developer

Phone: +977 9842070594

Email: ojasvitmg@gmail.com

GitLab: https://gitlab.com/lalamdorje

GitHub: https://github.com/ojasvi264

Summary

Skilled Software Engineer with 2years of hands-on experience building and optimizing web-based applications for diverse industry organizations. Friendly and engaging team player and an enthusiastic learner. Keen to learn and excel in the field of computer science and software development. Developed many web applications and passionate in becoming a full stack developer. Eager to gain new skills and experience to develop a carrier in it.

Technical Skills

Languages and Scripts: PHP, JavaScript, HTML5, CSS3

Frameworks and Libraries: Laravel, jQuery, AJAX, VueJs, Bootstrap

VCS: Git, Github, Gitlab

Database: MYSQL

Hosting: Web hosting

Collaboration: Slack

Professional Experience

Software Engineer: IET Technology Pvt. Ltd. (September 2022 - Present)

• Cooperate with backend developers to create software as per the documentation and planning, division of tasks, designing of database, roles and responsibilities.

- Working in development of complete school and college management software using PHP with laravel framework, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, jQuery and Ajax.
- Organizing meetings with developers and clients to establish a transparent relationship.
- Carry out quality assurance tests to discover errors and optimize usability.

Software Engineer: Softmahal Technologies Pvt. Ltd. (September 2021 – December 2022)

- Developed many web applications such as:
 - Online learning course "Simsime" for an institution.
 - o eBook store application "Ajambari".
 - Fruit shop website "Parbati Foods".
 https://parbatifoods.com.np/
 - News portal application "Bishwash Khabar".
 https://bishwashkhabar.com/

Jr. PHP Developer: Rolling Plans Pvt. Ltd. (October 2020 – July 2021)

- Worked on News Portal "Artharojgar".
- Gave a helping hand on "**Rolling Chalphal**" project for learners and students to discuss the queries and present their views.

Intern and Jr. Laravel Developer (Placement) + Field Supervisor: EasyAccess Pvt. Ltd. (June 2019 – July 2020)

- Worked on a "**Digital Profile**" project for the Solududhkunda Municipality of Solukhumbu District, Nepal.
- Organized the seminar and orientation project for the data collectors in Solukhumbu District.
- Data Collection and Evaluation, Debugging and Testing for the "**Digital Profile**".
- Learned to develop an eCommerce Website and an Event Managent System during the intern period.

Data Entry: CloudFactory (March 2018) – Deccember 2018)

• Worked on the "**Lighting**" project to classify various vehicles and objects from the radar scan of a self-driving cars. For training the model.

Major Projects

School Management Software

Link: https://emis.koshistjames.edu.np/

Link: https://jantacampus.edu.np/ (E-library System)

Roles:

- Planning, Designing of Database, Managing the work load among the teams
- Login, Roles, Responsibilities and Permissions analysis and design for the software.
- CRUD operation.
- Consulting with the designing team about the design and the layout of the software.
- Debugging and error handling.
- Web Hosting.

Nepal's Province1 Website

Link: https://pradeshsabha.koshi.gov.np/

Roles:

- Leading the Backend development team.
- Discuss and distribute the work load among the teams.
- Meeting with the clients for possible changes.
- Evaluation and Debugging.

Solukhumbu Municipality|Digital Profile

Roles:

- Database creation.(Using MYSQL)
- Backend CRUD operation (MVC Pattern).
- Debugging and error handling.

Education Tribhuvan University

Bachelor in Computer Science and Information Technology (BSc CSIT), Nagarjuna College of IT (Tribhuvan University) (2015 - 2019)